Angelina M.Cortes

LIBRARIAN/ ARCHIVIST

OBJECTIVE

To obtain a position where I can utilize my skills in information and data science, supervision, and be on a team that provides excellent customer service to our whole community.

EXPERIENCE

LIBRARIAN/SUPERVISOR - ADULT SERVICES

March 2014 - Current

San Antonio Public Library – Currently the Assistant Mgr. of the Adult Education Learn Center at Central. Responsible for creating and designing the new Learn at Central space from planning, developing programming and classes, office, budget, technology and hiring of Training Officers. Partnered with NTEN to become a Digital Equity Fellow to bring in \$9,000 for Digital Equity programming and training internally and to the community. Serve on a data analyst committee to revamp SAPLs information retrieval systems. Was selected to be a Project Manager of a system wide digital equity initiative to train older adults in iPads.

Sno-Isle Libraries -Monroe, WA - Worked as an adult reference librarian handling daily operations of a branch including all customer service points and collection maintenance. Side projects: Partnered with the Kellogg Foundation to become a Humanitarian scholar for ALA's Great Stories National Advisor Committee. Selected as a TEDx Curatorial Researcher to contact and vet applicants. Trained and worked as a DEI consultant to staff in DEAI best practices.

DIGITAL AND PRINT ARCHIVIST

April 2008 – August 2013

Accessioned, arranged, and designed metadata schemas with print and born digital documents building ContentDm sties, exhibited materials, developed, and planned long-term archival management as well as taught the community in archival research in the following institutions: University of Washington Seattle Special Collections, Daniel J. Evans' library, SHUMLA Private Archeological Library, Texas A&M San Antonio Archives, and Seattle Public Library Special Collections.

CONTACT

cortesporcz@gmail.com (206) 694.9738 San Antonio, TX 78216

ABOUT ME

I am passionate about information architecture, integrated design and how humans interpret and research information. I believe in providing authentic help and have worked in information hubs across the country for the past 20 years.

EDUCATION

University of Washington – Seattle 2010-2013

MLIS Focus on Archives Mgmt.
The Evergreen State College –
Olympia 2006-2008
BLA – History, Political Science and Creative Writing

SKILLS

MS Office Project management (PMI) Collection Development familiarity Collection Maintenance knowledge